<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Content on PHI 182a</title>
    <link>https://chreliot.github.io/phi182a/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Content on PHI 182a</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 15:26:52 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://chreliot.github.io/phi182a/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Assignment 2</title>
      <link>https://chreliot.github.io/phi182a/assignments/assignment-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 13:25:29 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chreliot.github.io/phi182a/assignments/assignment-2/</guid>
      <description>This essay offers you practice at interpreting and finding reasons in texts and then doing your own analysis. Write at least 1500 words, developing a response to the question below.
Write as if to a generally-competent reader who is not in the class and does not have a background in philosophy, rather than to, say, me. That means you will need to explain terms or concepts you mention, instead of assuming the reader has read the same material.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topic 3: Stoics</title>
      <link>https://chreliot.github.io/phi182a/topics/stoics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 11:35:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chreliot.github.io/phi182a/topics/stoics/</guid>
      <description>Like Socrates&amp;rsquo; vision of Philosophy and Epicureanism, Stoicism was for its ancient advocates most of all a way of living. Coming to understand what is really good, they argued, and how the good and happiness are rooted in nature, could lead us toward perfect lives.
Readings  Epictetus, The Handbook, text available on Blackboard &amp;gt; Course Documents. Epictetus, Discourses, download excerpts from Blackboard &amp;gt; Course Documents. (11 pages total) Seneca, from Letters on Ethics: To Lucilius (Univ.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topic 2: Epicureans</title>
      <link>https://chreliot.github.io/phi182a/topics/epicureans/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 08:24:20 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chreliot.github.io/phi182a/topics/epicureans/</guid>
      <description>Epicureanism is a philosophy that focused on how to be a happy person, especially in the face of challenges, though its understanding of what happiness is differs from a lot of common, current ideas about happiness. Epicureanism became so popular that it became a dominant religion in the Mediterranean world, especially during the Roman empire. We will read the original Epicurean, Epicurus, and then the most prominent and influential Epicurean author, Lucretius, whose work De Rerum Natura is widely described as a classic of world literature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topic 1: Socrates</title>
      <link>https://chreliot.github.io/phi182a/topics/socrates/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 12:19:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chreliot.github.io/phi182a/topics/socrates/</guid>
      <description>Reading (This section lists required readings and where to find them. For due dates, see the schedule page.)
 Plato, Apology, first part. Translated by GMA Grube, in Five Dialogues 2nd ed., pages 21–28. Or, see the PDF under Course Documents on Blackboard for a stopgap measure while you&amp;rsquo;re acquiring the books. Plato, Crito, translated by GMA Grube, in Five Dialogues 2nd ed. (12 pages total) Plato, Hippias Major in Socrates and the Sophists, tr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interpreting Grades</title>
      <link>https://chreliot.github.io/phi182a/info/interpreting-grades/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 19:55:28 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chreliot.github.io/phi182a/info/interpreting-grades/</guid>
      <description>This note about grading and interpreting grades just adds some detail to what the course syllabus already says about grading.
4-point scale Grades in this course are assigned and calculated using Hofstra&amp;rsquo;s 4-point scale (described here in the Hofstra Bulletin). Following the Bulletin, the alphabetical grades, including plus (+) and minus (–), have the following 4-point scale values (and vice versa):
   letter 4pt Student’s academic performance …     A 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Participation Rubric</title>
      <link>https://chreliot.github.io/phi182a/info/participation-rubric/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 21:25:39 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chreliot.github.io/phi182a/info/participation-rubric/</guid>
      <description>This is the participation rubric to be used for grading participation in this course. Read it as saying “A student who demonstrates … earns a grade of X,” where X is the letter grade at the top of the column.1
   A B C D F     Active role in discussions, drawing on texts Regular, constructive participation drawing on texts Inconsistent constructive participation based on texts Vague comments reflecting limited engagement with texts Persistent lack of engagement with texts   Full preparation for approximately every class Substantial preparation, normally Inconsistent evidence of preparation Rare evidence of participation No positive evidence of participation   Success at advancing level and depth of discussion, persistently Regular contributions based on assigned material, which sometimes improve discussion and never diminish it Rare or no significant contribution to the level of discussion while not reducing it Activity sometimes diminishing the discussion and the classroom environment Activity regularly diminishing the discussion and the classroom environment   Active engagement with and listening to peers, persistently Sincere efforts to interact with peers, normally Limited engagement with peers Rare interaction with peers No interaction with peers      This rubric is significantly based on, and lightly adapted from, one written by another philosophy professor, Jay Odenbaugh.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Timeline</title>
      <link>https://chreliot.github.io/phi182a/info/timeline/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2018 12:48:37 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chreliot.github.io/phi182a/info/timeline/</guid>
      <description>My timeline of the lives of Socrates, Plato, the Epicureans, and the Stoics we will read is here (PDF) and below. Red is for Socratics, Grey is for Epicureans, and Red is for Stoics.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>